欢迎加入OCR小组 qq群906722936 字幕优先发布于群内
前情提要
特伦查德大人 全额付款
Lord Trenchard. Payment in full.
啊 他家夫人十分美丽
Ah. He of the beautiful wife.
埃勒比医生
Dr. Ellerby.
艺术展览的邀请函
An invitation to an art exhibition.
这位医生倒是很执着
He's persistent, the doctor.
他是在表示友好罢了
He's being friendly, that's all.
嘘 跟我来
Shh. Follow me.
你知道那家炼钢厂吗
You know about the steel foundry?
我在考虑对它投资
I'm thinking of investing in it.
一大笔钱 老爷
A lot of money, Your Lordship.
看来您满意了 夫人
You're satisfied then, madame.
我希望名下的所有投资都一帆风顺
I wish all my investments ran as smoothly.
希望不久再合作新项目
We must plan another venture together soon.
也许吧
Perhaps.
-你怎么了  -我想起了我的父亲
·What is it? - I was thinking about my father.
他一定会为你骄傲的
He'd be proud of you, surely.
我个人认为 逃避不良情绪
Personally, I think it's in our natures
是人的天性
to run away from difficult feelings.
但只要鼓起勇气面对
But if we have the courage to confront them,
就能放下很多痛苦
we can let go of a great deal of pain.
我哥最近怎么样
How is my brother?
他对他父亲有些心结 并深受其困
He is very much troubled by thoughts of his father.
你要是能跟弗雷德里克谈谈 会大有裨益
It might help Frederick if you would speak to him.
你想把她变成你的朋友
You thought you would befriend her
然后在她耳边说我坏话
and whisper poison in her ears about me?
- 不 我没有  -请你离开我家
- No, I didn't. - Leave my house!
你背着我去见他了
You went behind my back.
-你为什么要这么做  -我不知情啊
Why would you do that? - I didn't know.
你第一次见他是什么时候
When did you first meet him?
一个多星期前
A little over a week ago.
在哪儿见的
Where?
我说过了 我去了牧师住宅
I told you. I went to the vicarage.
就一次
Once.
你是了解我的
You know me well enough.
你知道我心里只有你
You know I think only of you.
我以为能帮你解开心结
I thought it might help you.
你的内心 藏了太多的痛苦
You have so much pain locked in your heart.
你就是这么看我的 一个需要救助的
That's how you see me? As some injured creature
-受伤动物  -不
who must be helped? - No.
-这是他暗示你的吧  -不
- Is that what he implied? - No.
他都说我什么了
What did he say about me?
他说你跟你父亲有过节
That there was a rift with your father,
这不是你造成的
which was not of your making.
-真有雅量啊  -他说他很想你
·How magnanimous. - He said he misses you,
他渴望与你和解
that he longs to be reconciled.
他表现得真诚 弗雷德里克
He seemed genuine, Frederick.
说实话 我依然相信 只要你们能坐下来聊聊
Honestly, I still believe that if you could only talk together.
你根本不了解他
You don't know him.
你知道他有个弟弟吗
Did you know he had a brother?
当然知道
Of course I did.
两个男生在格兰维尔长大时
Mr. Enright and I were at Glanville
就是恩莱特先生和我在伺候了
when the two boys were growing up.
所以是发生了什么
So, what went on?
两人肯定是有天大的矛盾
It must've been an almighty falling out.
不知道
Don't know.
很多兄弟都有矛盾
Lots of brothers fall out.
对 可是
Yeah, but...
我也总跟我哥闹矛盾
I fell out of my lot all the time.
我是说 我们会吵架
I mean, we had fights,
也会打架 一连打上好几小时
punch- ups that went on for hours.
-是吗  -当然
Did you? - Of course.
但等你俩坐在桌前
But then you sit down at the table,
妈妈端上来一碗热乎乎的炖菜时
and your ma gives you a bowl of stew
矛盾就到此结束
·and that's the end of it. -
他们要上去了
They're going up.
这件事今后谁也不许再提 无论是在府内还是府外
None of this is to be discussed outside this house or in it.
希望大家都能理解
I hope that's understood.
明白
It is.
都解散吧
Off you go.
-晚安 恩薰特先生  -晚安
·Good night then, Mr. Enright. - Good night.
所以 这俩兄弟还闹着矛盾呢
So, things are still bad between the brothers.
似乎是这样
Seems that way.
他俩的事我从没弄明白过
I never really understood.
是嫉妒吗
Is it jealousy?
-是竞争吗  -我知道的不比你多
Rivalry? - I know no more than you.
我天天困在厨房里 能知道什么
What do I see stuck in the kitchen all day?
你怎么这么难受 人都在抖
Why does it bother you so much? You're shaking.
我辜负了他
I failed him.
我应该想法子提醒他的 玛德琳
I should have found a way to warn him, Madeleine.
他是个成年人了 也该会自己处理麻烦了
He's a grown man. Let him deal with his own mess.
用的是我奶奶的食谱
From my grandmama's recipe.
当然 我很少冒险下厨
I rarely venture into the kitchen, of course,
但如果您吃起来不错
but if it meets with your approval,
我打算做五个 拿到蛋糕摊上去卖
I shall be supplying five for the cake stall.
这是我吃过的最好吃的水果蛋糕
That is the finest fruit cake I have ever tasted.
我吃过的蛋糕也不少
And I have tasted a good many.
那好 就这么定了
Good. That's decided then.
我就甩开膀子干了
I shall set my shoulder to the wheel.
谢谢你
Thank you.
听说您见过我妹妹了
I hear you met my sister.
对的 相见甚欢
I did. It was a pleasure.
当然 她很有魅力
Oh, yes, she's all charm.
苛以及时到
...there in good time.
我们时间算得不错 夫人
I...I think we timed that well, Your Ladyship.
天再过半个小时会很热
It'll be so hot in half an hour
散步就不会很适宜了
that there'd be no pleasure in a walk.
我能做些什么吗
How can I help?
给夫人的信
Your Ladyship.
我让他们您倒点咖啡来吧 夫人
Shall I ask them to bring you some coffee, Your Ladyship?
好的 拜托
Yes, please.
戴维森
Davison?
-牧师  -请原谅
Reverend. - Forgive me.
我只求您给我五分钟
Five minutes of your time is all I ask.
我想这是我们最后一次见面了
I think this will be the last time we ever meet.
恐怕你说的对
I fear that's true.
我想对你说两件事
I want to say two things to you.
很抱歉昨天直接登门贵府
I am so sorry I came to the house yesterday.
我不该那么做的
I should never have done that.
是我的错 我给了你希望
It was my fault. I gave you hope.
我 我一想到自己让你跟
I...I can't live with the thought
弗雷德里克起了隔阂 就很过意不去
that I've caused difficulty between you and Frederick.
特伦查德夫人 请别他的表现
Lady Trenchard, please don't think badly of him
和这些事影响他在你心中的看法
for the way he behaved yesterday or for any of this.
这不能怪他
He's not to blame.
请您保证会永远记得这一点
Please tell me you will always remember that.
我真希望能多了解一些
I wish I understood more about what happened with your father,
你们父子之间的事
and with you.
他的态度非常 强硬
His attitude is so...entrenched.
你们是发生了什么特别的事吗
Was there one particular event?
是大吵了一架吗
An argument?
他提到 你父亲临终时
He mentioned that when your father was dying,
只想让你陪在床边
he wanted only you at his bedside.
这是真的吗
Is that true?
这
It.
这是我父亲的决定
It was my father's decision.
我不能违背他的意愿
And I couldn't go against his wishes.
那你母亲呢 她就没劝劝他吗
And what of your mother? Couldn't she have persuaded him?
家母是一位坚强美丽的女人
Our mother was a strong and beautiful woman,
但她同时也希望别人
but she expected the same strength
像她一样坚强
in everyone else.
那在她去世时
And when she died,
应该是想见到弗雷迪里克的吧
please tell me she wanted Frederick there.
她想见
She did.
非常想见他
Very much.
她专门提出见他
She asked for him.
你们是那个时候闹了矛盾吗
And did anything happen between you then?
那是你们最后一次见面吗
Was that the last time you saw one another?
他没能过来
He wasn't able to come.
但他来参加了葬礼 可我们没有说话
But he came to the funeral, though we didn't speak.
她临终时
He didn't go to her...
他没去见她
when she was dying?
为什么呢
Why?
我觉得
I think.
也许是因为恐惧
perhaps it was the fear,
也许会激起他对家父去世的回忆
the memory of our father's death.
也许他不来更好
Perhaps it was better that he didn't come.
你怎么会这么说呢
How can you say so?
没有什么能阻止我见父亲最后一面
Nothing would have kept me from my father's deathbed.
他受伤极深
The wounds are deep.
你知道吗
Do you see?
是经年累月的
It was years...
任何人都难以承受这种伤害
It would be too much for any soul.
我总觉得
I can't help feeling
你还有事瞒着我
that there's something you're not telling me.
很抱歉这么说 但有没有什么信息
I'm sorry, but if there's anything, anything at all,
能帮我更好地了解他 什么信息都行
which might help me to understand him better.
我只能说到这里了
There is no more to be said.
失去他我也很悲伤
My own sadness at the loss of him,
这是我必须承受的
I must bear...
我也会承受
I will bear.
但 但请向我保证 他会永远
But...But I have to know that he will always,
永远拥有你的爱和支持
always have your love and support.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这不是他的错
He was not to blame.
所以 我想问问各位女士
So, I'm asking the ladies if they have experience
有没有照顾大象的经验
in looking after the elephants. -
那只白象 亲爱的海蒂
The white elephant, Hetty dear.
白象摊位
White Elephant Stall.
这个职位蛮特别的
It's a very different proposition.
我们又不招驯象员
We are not recruiting mahouts.
看到了吗
You see there?
他们重新加入了碳和锰
They're reintroducing carbon and manganese.
份量不多不少
Exact amount.
真厉害 非常厉害
Damned impressive! Damned impressivel
就像地狱之口
Like the mouth of hell!
-你果然是懂行的  -那当然
I'm glad you're able to see it. - I'll say.
谢谢你邀请我过来
Thank you for inviting me.
想想看 这个工厂会全年无休地开工
To think that is going all day, every day...
-日夜不停  -太棒了
And through the night. - It's astonishing.
敬你一杯 这个聪明鬼
Well, to you, my clever friend,
以及他不断扩张的王国 伦敦东区异类
and his expanding kingdom, the strange land of East End.
难怪连侯爵夫人都被你打动了
No wonder the Marquise is so impressed by you.
她总是对你赞不绝口
Never tires of singing your praises.
你知道她有个新项目 还想邀我一起干吗
You know she's trying to enlist me into this new scheme of hers.
她也邀请你了吧 一定请了
Did you put her up to it? I suspect you did.
啊是的
Ah, yes.
-哪一个  -银矿那个
Which one? - The silver mine.
在墨西哥
Mexico.
估计我在地图上都找不到
Doubt I could place it on a map.
但她对这个项目似乎很有信心 对吧
She seems utterly confident in the venture, doesn't she?
你怎么看
What do you think of it?
显然 我还需要更多信息
Well, I need more information, of course.
太对了
Quite right.
涉及到数字的地方 我就不知道了
The figures involved. I had no idea.
我告诉她 做生意我不太在行
I told her business isn't my bag.
你知道吗
Do you know what?
但作为一个小投资来说 还挺令人兴奋的
For a first little foray, it seems rather thrilling.
去异国土地上淘金
"Untold riches in an exotic land. "
她什么时候跟你提的 我好奇问一下
When did she mention it to you? Out of interest.
大约一周前
About a week ago.
怎么 我错过截止日期了吗
Don't tell me I've missed the deadline.
嗯 没 没有
Uh...no.
至少我不这么认为
At least I don't think so.
我跟着你投就对了
I shall be led by you.
今后就是合作伙伴了哈
Rather jolly to be partners, what?
我觉得过几天
I thought we might go out together
咱俩可以出门走走
sometime in the next few days.
我之前跟你说过的画展
The exhibition of paintings I mentioned.
还记得吗
Do you remember?
就是明天
It's tomorrow.
咱俩一起去好不好
I thought we might attend together.
恐怕我抽不出时间
I'm afraid I can't spare the time,
但你要是想去就去吧
but you should go if you'd like to.
一个人去吗
Alone?
不过我有点弄不懂
Although I must say I'm surprised,
邀请函不是埃勒比医生寄来的吗
was the invitation not from Dr. Ellerby?
对但据我所知 展出的作品不是他的
Yes, but the works are not his, from what I understand.
他只想引起我们的注意
He was simply bringing it to our attention.
也许罗切斯特一家也会去
I thought the Rochesters might attend.
估计不会
- - I doubt they will.
那咱们千点别的吧
Well, let's do something else then.
我觉得如果有机会
It might be good for us
-我们可以  -克拉拉
to have the opportunity to- - - Clara.
我已经认真想过了 我希望
I have thought on this, and it is my wish...
你我努力忘掉昨天的不愉快
that we endeavor to forget the events of yesterday.
弗雷德里克
Frederick- -
虽然我费了很大地劲儿
I accept, albeit with some difficulty,
才理解你想办好事的初衷
that you thought your actions might be helpful.
我理解这一点
I accept it.
但坦白讲 我不想每晚坐在餐桌旁
But frankly, I cannot sit at dinner every night,
都等着我妻子又一次提出那个
wondering when my wife will insist on raising matters
只会给我带来不悦的问题
that can only be the cause of the deepest discomfort to me.
我希望你能理解
I hope you are able to understand that.
我能理解 是的
I am able to understand it. Yes.
我并不是想
I didn't mean...
拜托 求你了 今后别再提了
Please...Please, can we leave it at that?
抱歉 我只是得了些闲空
Sorry. I had a few minutes to spare.
千万别道歉
Please don't apologize.
我能问你个问题吗 牧师
May I ask you a question, Reverend?
当然可以
Of course.
你觉得人死后会孤单吗
Do you think the dead feel lonely?
我不觉得
No. I don't.
我觉得天堂是一个充满爱和温暖的地方
I think those in heaven feel awash with warmth and love.
可那些没进天堂的人呢
What if they aren't in heaven?
他们并非是自己犯了错
Through no fault of their own.
神就是爱
God is love
神永远不会拒绝
and would never turn someone away
一个无辜的人
if they were innocent.
孤独是种人世的痛苦
Loneliness is an earthly affliction.
即便一屋子坐满了人
We can feel lonely
我们还是会感到痛苦 不是吗
even in a room full of people, can't we?
你是在为某人担心吗 内尔
Are you concerned about someone in particular, Nell?
牧师 你在这里
Ah, Reverend, here you are.
邓恩小姐 你还好吗
Miss Dunn. How are you getting on?
能占用你几分钟宝贵的时间吗
Might we have a few minutes of your precious time?
我得在明天之前告诉印刷商
Only I have to deliver the wording of the handbook
手册的内容
to the printers by the end of tomorrow.
筹资目标
The fundraising objectives.
我本该帮你写下来的
I was supposed to write them down for you.
没事的
Please don't worry.
我自己冒昧地列了几项
I've taken the liberty of outlining a few myself.
钟表维修需要15英镑
Repairs to the clock at 15 pounds.
墓墙维修 你说过是38英镑
Cemetery wall repairs, I think you mentioned at 38 pounds.
天 您的记忆真是超群
My goodness. What a memory.
对对 咱们现在就敲定
Yes, yes. Let's look at them now.
内尔 客气提醒下 这些茶杯需要洗了
The teacups need washing, Nell, if you don't mind.
下午好
Good afternoon.
-欢迎  -谢谢
- Welcome. - Thank you.
这是展品目录 供您阅读
Our catalogue, if you would care to look.
我是迪尔登先生 参展人之一
Mr. Dearden. I'm one of the exhibitors.
我喜欢提前表明身份
I always think it best to mention that
以免别人说出什么话令我伤心
before someone says something which breaks my heart.
能告诉我您叫什么吗
And might I have your name?
当然 特伦查德夫人
Of course. Lady Trenchard.
是埃勒比医生邀请我来的
I received an invitation from Dr. Ellerby.
对对 您能来真是太好了
Yes. Yes. How kind of you to come.
斯蒂芬 埃勒比医生一定会很开心的
Stephen- - Dr. Ellerby- will be delighted.
但恐怕他现在不在
I'm afraid he isn't here at present.
那罗切斯特公爵夫人在里面吗
Is the Duchess of Rochester here, perhaps?
她之前还在
She was, earlier.
要我带你四处看看吗 特伦查德夫人
Would you like me to show you around, Lady Trenchard?
-我乐意为您效劳  -谢谢
- I would gladly. - Thank you.
我自己逛就可以了
I shall manage very well.
如果需要 我随时都在
I'm here if you have need of me.
我没听说过银矿的事 老爷
I've heard nothing at all about a silver mine, Your Lordship.
-不然我一定会记得  -可你还是忘了
- I'd remember if I had. - Then you should have done.
你炫耀自己人脉时倒是很积极
You're quick enough to boast about your contacts.
我能问一下背后老板是谁吗
May I ask who's behind the scheme?
要不要我去问问他们
Would you like me to make inquiries of them?
不用了 我自己会处理
No. I shall deal with it myself.
我要是听到什么消息 立刻通知您
If I hear anything at all, I shall alert you at once,
请您一定放心
You may depend on it.
特伦查德夫人正在看的那幅
Lady Trenchard is looking at it now.
精巧绝伦 不是吗
Extraordinary, isn't it?
埃勒比医生
Dr. Ellerby.
特伦查德女士
Lady Trenchard.
-戴维森小姐  -先生
Miss Davison. - Sir.
大人跟您一起来的吗
Is His Lordship with you?
-遗憾 他没有  -那我就更感激您
·Unfortunately not. - Then I'm all the more grateful
专程来赴约了
that you took the trouble to come.
您以前参观过画廊吗
Have you ever visited a gallery before?
有过一次 是和我父亲一起
Once, with my father.
是在皇家艺术学院
It was at the Royal Academy.
但都不如这幅画风格独特
There was certainly nothing in this style.
这话你一定爱听 迪尔登
That should be music to your ears, Dearden.
特伦查德夫人 请允许我介绍
Lady Trenchard, allow me to present- -
我已有幸认识过了
I've already had the pleasure.
这是你的作品吗 迪尔登先生
This is one of your works, Mr. Dearden?
是的
It is.
很美
It's beautiful.
情感丰富 难以言说
And emotional, somehow.
您真是太过奖了
I couldn't have hoped for a kinder review.
-你看过罗塞蒂的画作吗  -对
·Have you seen the Rossettis? - Mm.
我跟他比起来要苍白得多
Mine rather pale beside his.
我持不同看法
I can't agree with you.
对 那些作品很吸引人
Yes, they're arresting.
他是我的偶像
He's my idol...
您大概也看出来了
as you can probably tell. -
他一会儿会跟莫里斯夫人过来
We expect him later, with Mrs. Morris.
如果你能留下的话 我可以介绍你们认识
If you're able to stay, I will gladly introduce you.
恐怕我现在得走了
I'm afraid I have to leave now.
-谢谢  -也许下次吧
- Thank you. - To the next time, perhaps.
那我送您出去
Allow me to see you out.
您来时我不在 真是抱歉
I'm so sorry I wasn't here when you arrived.
我每周出两次诊
I help at a mission twice a week.
今天的病人比平时多
And we had more patients than usual today.
你在梅伍德给我的建议
The advice you gave me at Maywood,
鼓励人们直面恐惧的那一条
about encouraging people to confront their fears.
怎么了
Yes?
如果想帮忙的那个人
Do you think it's possible to push too hard...
逼得太紧 会不会把困难复杂化
and to compound the difficulty where one was trying to help?
我认为任何人
I think anyone who's being asked
被问到自己害怕的东西
to look at something that frightens them
一定会表现出一些阻力
is bound to show some resistance.
甚至对抗
Antagonism, even.
我认为 他们内心深处
I would say that some part of them,
无论埋得多深
no matter how deeply buried,
总得自己作出改变
would have to want to change.
希望我的建议没太冒昧
I hope my advice wasn't ill- judged.
你还好吗
How are you?
请别介意我这么说 但你看上去有点伤心
You seem a little sad, if you don't mind my saying.
我很好
I'm perfectly well.
您见过艺术家的工作室吗
Have you ever seen inside an artist studio?
或者观看过艺术家创作吗
Or watched an artist at work?
我跟迪尔登住在一起
I lodge with Dearden,
他的工作室很有意思 值得一看
and his studio is really something to see.
如果您想来参观
If you would ever care to visit. ...
他一定会荣幸至极
I know he would be honored.
谢谢你告诉我
I'll bear it in mind.
对不起 邓恩小姐
Sorry, Miss Dunn.
你的演奏技艺是哪里学的
Where on earth did you learn to play like that?
我 嗯
I...um...
这不是什么简单小调
It's hardly a music hall ditty.
是肖邦吧
Chopin, wasn't it?
我只是对曲调过耳不忘
I...hear tunes, and they stay with me.
但你是从哪里听到的呢
But where could you have heard it?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
好吧
Right.
可你却记得所有音符
And yet you remember all the notes.
这天赋真有意思
It's quite a gift.
家务都做好了吗
Is everything tidied away?
好的 小姐 我这就去拿工具
Yes, miss. I'll fetch my things.
你们茶都吃完了吗
And did you eat all your tea?
吃完了 爸爸
Yes, Papa.
好孩子
Good man.
好了好了 去找保姆吧
Now, now, come on, back to Nanny.
我跟你一起上楼去看彼得
And I shall come upstairs with you and see Peter.
我能见彼得吗
Can I see Peter?
彼得病了 对吗
Peter is ill, isn't he?
他不希望你也生病
He doesn't wish for you to get ill.
我会帮你多亲亲他的
I'll give him a kiss from you.
你觉得迪尔登先生的画作如何
What did you think of Mr. Dearden's paintings?
我欣赏不来
They weren't to my taste.
太华丽了 虽然介绍上写着
Too florid. For all the words written in there
自然的真实再现
about a"true representation of nature, "
反正看起来跟我熟悉的大自然毫不相干
I should say it didn't look anything like the nature I know.
我觉得太过夸张浪漫了
I should say it was overblown and overly romantic.
过于浪漫”难道是坏事吗
I'm not sure anything can be"overly romantic. "
那是因为你还年轻 夫人
That's because you're young, Your Ladyship.
我就先走了 牧师
I shall get off now, Reverend.
我留了一些冷盘
I've left some cold cuts on the side,
还留了汤 想喝的话可以喝
and there's soup if you'd like it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你想跟我一起吃吗
Would you care to join me?
哦 恐怕不行
Oh, I'm afraid I can't.
我女儿和她家人还等着我呢
My daughter and her family are waiting.
-好吧  -不过谢谢你了 先生
Good. - But thank you, sir.
那就明早见
I shall see you in the morning.
-晚安  -晚安 沃伦夫人
·Good night. - Good night, Mrs. Warren.
他还没回来吗
He's not back then?
还没有
Not yet.
他应该在俱乐部吧
I believe he is at his club.
事业跟婚姻都不顺心
Difficult business, marriage.
似乎的确如此
Seems so.
你自己从没想过结婚吗
You never thought of it for yourself, then?
我习惯了自由自在
I like my own way too much.
你呢
You?
一样
The same.
谢谢您 老爷
Thank you, Your Lordship.
我出去散个步
Going for an evening stroll.
在我锁门之前回来
Back before I lock up.
-谢谢  -谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
你不是要给我拿煤吗
I thought you were fetching me some coal.
当然 恩莱特太太 别担心
Certainly am, Mrs. Enright. Never fear.
麻烦给我一张邮票
A stamp for this, please.
要寄到哪里
Where's it going?
不识字吗
Can't read?
你自然是不识字的 给我吧
Of course you can't. Pass it here.
-信是寄到哪里的  -放信箱吧
·Where is it goin- - In the box.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
信箱
老爷走了吗
His Lordship has left?
是的 夫人
Yes, Your Ladyship.
他早上有会
An early appointment.
但这是穆克罗夫特医生交代的 殿下
But it was Dr. Moorcroft's orders, Your Grace.
我没有怪你 道斯
I'm not blaming you, Dawes.
下次医生来了 我会亲自跟他说
I will speak to the doctor myself on his next visit.
但在此之前 不要增加剂量了
But until then, I do not want the dose increased.
我可怜的儿子已经睡得够多了
The poor boy sleeps enough as it is.
是的 陛下
Yes, Your Grace.
谢谢你 去照顾他吧
Thank you. Please return to him.
有问题吗 亲爱的
Problem, my dear?
有问题也你不需要担心
Not one you need concern yourself with...
再说你也不愿去担心
or would wish to, it seems.
-你在干什么 亲爱的  -哦 母亲
- What are you doing, dear? - Oh! Mother!
你非要这样吗
Must you?
怎样
What?
-鬼鬼祟祟的  -我没有鬼鬼祟祟
Creep. - Oh, I wasn't creeping.
我以为你是内尔
I...I thought you were Nell.
她去商店了 亲
She's at the shop, dear.
我知道
I know.
我手帕丢了 我以为
I've mislaid a handkerchief, and I thought.
她洗衣服时 把我的和她的
she might have mixed it up with one of hers...
弄混了
in the wash.
你该不会觉得
You don't think she's...
她在偷东西吧
stealing from us, do you?
那也太可怕了
I mean, that would be too dreadful.
你说什么啊
I beg your pardon?
但仔细想 我们对她确实知之甚少
I suppose wewe do know so little about her.
我不是在暗示什么
I wasn't implying that at all.
天哪 你也太阴暗太多疑了
Good heavens, what a dark and suspicious mind you have.
好了出来吧 妈妈 我们不该来这里
Well, come out, Mother. We shouldn't be in here.
对
Right.
-特伦查德大人  -怎么了
Lord Trenchard? - Yes.
夫人在等你
Madame is expecting you.
在摸着石头过了一阵子河后
There's been some trial and error,
我们已经取得了收支平衡
but we now seem to have the balance exactly right.
我希望下周能与
I fully expect to be signing a deal
大东方公司敲定协议
with Great Eastern next week
为他们扩建工程提供轨道
to provide the rails for their latest expansion.
真是好消息 弗雷德里克
This is excellent, Frederick.
我们打算从薄板生产转为毛坯生产
We mean to switch to producing"blooms"rather than sheets.
因为毛坯刚更适合制造铁轨
They're better suited to the manufacture of rails.
这房子一切都没个条理
This house. I live in chaos.
但不会太久了
But not for much longer.
这是我们修改后的计划
I've prepared our revised projections.
如果这笔生意能谈成 我希望谈成
If I secure the deal, as I intend to,
明年下半年我们就会盈利
we should be profitable in the second half of next year.
这比预期提前了6个月
Six months earlier than anticipated.
我跑了己千英里过来 不想再等了
I've traveled 2, 000 miles, and I will not be put off!
请您稍等 先生
Please wait, monsieur!
我被你深深折服了 弗雷德里克
I am greatly impressed, Frederick.
我必须承认 我们的成功超出了我的预期
Well, I must say our success has surpassed my expectations
也吊起了我继续
and has given me an appetite
合作类似规模
to look for schemes on a similar scale,
甚至更大项目的胃口
or larger, in fact.
当然 您是一个真正的企业家
Of course. You are a true entrepreneur.
您的胃口永远不会被满足
I doubt you will ever be satisfied.
我对投资机会永远持开放态度
I would always be open to investment opportunities here...
无论是国内还是国外
or abroad.
好的 没问题
Good. Yes.
拜托
· Please...
别 布里克斯先生 请稍等
Non, Monsieur Bricus. Wait!
天啊 真的很抱歉
Mon dieu. I'm so sorry.
我帮您问一下她 拜托别往前走了
I will ask if she will see you. Stop at once!
别碰我
Get your hands off of mel
布里卡斯先生
Mr. Bricus?
我的钱就低人一等吗
What is wrong with my money, huh? Huh?
请你冷静一下好吗
May I suggest you calm down?
你先来找我的 你带着银矿项目先来找的我
You came to me. You came to me first with the silver mine,
可我现在只能眼睁睁看着朋友赚得盆满钵满
and now I am watching my friends make money hand over fist- -
那些我推荐给你的朋友
friends I sent to you.
别嚷嚷了 布里卡斯先生
You need to stop shouting, Mr. Bricus.
我的钱就低人一等吗
What's wrong with my money?
我只想小心行事 仅此而已
I am careful. That is all.
我要对所有的投资人负责
I have a responsibility to all my investors.
而您这样 哭天抢地大喊大叫
In the meantime, begging and shouting
也绝不会达到你的目的
will not advance your cause.
等等
Wait.
太不好意思了 真的 让您看到这尴尬一幕
I am mortified. Really, I am so embarrassed.
我能帮忙吗
Can I help?
不用 谢谢你
No. Thank you.
福尔德太太会送您出去的
Madame Fourcade will show you out.
-你好啊  -抱歉 我很忙
·Hello. - I'm afraid I'm busy.
你今天过得怎么样
How was your day?
我今天一句话就能概括
It won't take long to tell you about mine.
独自度过 无事可做
I spent it alone, with nothing to do.
不好意思 这事很紧急 所以
Forgive me, this is urgent, so...
比我们的婚姻还急吗
More urgent than our marriage?
对不起
Sorry.
你找我什么事
Did you need me for something?
我想跟你定个日子
I was hoping we might settle on a day
邀请罗切斯特一家过来共进晚餐
to ask the Rochesters to dine with us.
明天不是要跟他们吃午饭吗
Are we not lunching with them tomorrow?
是的
Yes.
但我想回报他们的美意
But I would like to be able to reciprocate.
他们最近总是盛情款待我们
We've enjoyed a great deal of their hospitality of late.
我们还能邀请侯爵夫人
We could invite the Marquise as- -
我不知道 日子你自己看着定吧
I don't know. You may settle on a date if you wish.
我怎么能定呢
How can I?
我们这个状态
How can I invite people here...
我怎么好邀请别人过来 或是出游 或是做些其他事呢
or go anywhere or do anything when we are like this?
这事我一人解决不了 你得帮帮我
I can't solve this on my own. You have to help me.
我没要求你做什么
I'm not asking you to do anything.
我告诉你我的感受了 我们需要时间
I've told you what I feel, that we need time.
除此之外 我对你别无所求
I'm asking nothing else of you.
但我想让你对我有所求
But I want you to ask things of me.
我需要你这么做
I need you to.
克拉拉 我
Clara, I
拜托
Please.
我今天过得很艰难
It has been a difficult day.
我需要处理一些事
I'm trying to deal with something- -
一些你不愿告诉我的事
Which you do not wish to share with me.
我说过我会努力忘记的
I have said I will endeavor to forget.
可你把我拒之门外
But you will shut me out.
你考虑过我的感受吗
Have you once thought of my feelings in all of this?
考虑过我的痛苦吗
Of what I am suffering?
是的
Yes...
也许 你无法接受
Perhaps...you will not accept love
别人向你伸出援手 主动向你表达爱意
from those who offer it, who reach for you,
是因为你选择不去接受
because you choose not to.
你是有些自私在身上的
There's a selfishness in you
我之前没意识到
which I didn't know was there.
这是我吗 我的鼻子 给我个鼻子好吗
Is that me? Where's my nose? May I have a nose...
-你的拉丁语怎么样  -挺好的
·And how's your Latin? - Good.
哦 殿下
Oh, Your Grace...
他醒着吗
Is he awake?
醒着的 陛下
Yes, Your Grace.
瞧瞧啊
Well, well.
看看你
Look at you.
对不起 我好久没来看你了
Sorry I haven't been in to see you for a while.
这父亲不太称职
Fathers...eh?
你喜欢读这个 对吗
This is what you enjoy reading, is it?
马默杜克《淘气小猫的故事》
Marmaduke, The Tale of a Mischievous Kitten.
淘气
"Mischievous"?
用来形容我挺合适
Could be me.
大家总是说我很淘气
People tell me I'm mischievous all the time.
但我更像是一只又大又邋遢的狗
Though I think I'm more of a big, sloppy dog.
你觉得呢
Don't you think?
我们一起读好不好
Shall we read it together?
马默杜克 那只淘气的小猫
"Marmaduke, the mischievous kitten,
蜷曲着躺在篮子里
lay curled in a basket
-跟他的  -兄弟姐妹在一起
with his..."- "Brothers and sisters. "
所有的猫都是白底黑点
"The kittens were white with black patches,
除了马默杜克 他是
all except Marmaduke, who was..."
橘色的
"Orange. "
橘色
Orange?
我好像从没见过橘色的猫 你见过吗
I don't think I've ever seen an orange cat before. Have you?
所有的小猫都睡着了
"AII of the kittens were asleep,
爱打呼噜猫在打着呼噜
snoring little kitten snores.
爱做梦的小猫在做梦
Dreaming little kitten dreams.
突然间
And suddenly there was a..."
砰的一声
"Thump. "
从走廊那头传来
"...from down the hall..."
-他接下来能睡着吗  -当然
Will he sleep now? - Oh, yes.
莫克罗夫特开了一堆催眠药
Moorcroft and his bromide'll see to that.
他睡着的时间比醒着时还要多
He spends more time asleep than he does awake.
他不该过这样的生活
This is no life for him.
他应该有更丰富的人生
He's so much more than this.
我们漂亮的儿子
Our beautiful boy.
夫人
Your Ladyship?
您确定要去吗
Are you quite certain of this?
很抱歉 但去公共画廊是一回事
I'm sorry, but a public gallery is one thing,
可这里是男人的私人住宅
but this is a gentleman's private residence.
但这里是个工作室 一个画室
But it is also a studio. An atelier.
我也不是一个人 还有你陪着我
And I'm not alone. You're with me.
夫人
Your Ladyship.
天啊 真是意外之喜
Good heavens. What an exquisite surprise.
这位是米内特
This is Minette.
请进 请进
Come in. Come in, please.
好姑娘 真是个好姑娘
Oh, good girl, good girl. Such a good girl.
米内特是安妮的女儿
- Minette is Annie's daughter.
你见过安妮了吗 应该没有
Did you meet Annie? Perhaps not.
你只在画里见过她
You saw her in the painting.
你来得正好 理查德就在工作室
Your timing couldn't be better. Richard's just in his studio.
我正希望能看看
That's what I was hoping to see.
当然可以 迪尔登 来客人了
Of course. Uh, Dearden? Visitors.
那 我们帮您拿外套
Please, um, allow me to take your coats.
好的
Right.
欢迎 夫人
Welcome, Your Ladyship.
谢谢你 迪尔登先生
Thank you, Mr. Dearden.
叫我理查德就行
Richard, please.
能有这个机会参观我感激不尽
I'm grateful for this opportunity.
这是安妮·哈珀小姐
This is Miss Annie Harper.
-您好  -您好
How do you do? - How do you do?
我好像刚见过你女儿了
I think I just met your little girl.
她真漂亮
She's beautiful.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这个地方真是安难以置信
I can hardly believe this place.
我就知道你会喜欢的
I thought you'd like it.
像是炼金术室一样
It's like a kind of alchemy.
确实是
It is.
-你介意吗  -完全不介意
·Do you mind? - Not at all.
狄多 迦太基女王
Dido, Queen of Carthage.
摄人心魄
It's enchanting.
这离我画完还远着呢
It's far from finished.
他这人完全不会接受夸奖
He doesn't know how to take a compliment.
-还有这一幅  -画了好几个月了
And this...Months of work.
我还在找寻我的珀蒂塔
I'm still searching for my Perdita,
说起来真是讽刺
which is a little ironic.
不知道您愿不愿意赏光 夫人
I don't suppose you'd oblige, m'lady?
抱歉
Sorry...
只不过在画廊见您第一眼 我就有此意
Only I thought it in the gallery as soon as I saw you.
谢谢你 但还是不了
Thank you. I think not.
看来我得继续找了
The search continues.
您想来几笔吗
Would you like to?
不敢
I daren't.
没关系 我可以覆盖掉的
I can always paint over it.
稍稍画几笔 来吧
The slightest touch.
你现在是个艺术家了
Now you're an artist. -
我们打算吃点东西
We're gonna have something to eat.
有几个朋友要过来
Some friends are joining us.
欢迎你留下加入
I hope you'll stay.
你应该留下
You should.
其中两位刚从巴黎回来
Two of them are just back from Paris.
可以听他们讲讲故事
There'll be tales to tell.
您一会儿还有约在身 夫人
You have your engagement, Your Ladyship.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们等会几就要去罗切斯特家赴约了
We shall be leaving for the Rochesters' soon.
就不需要备马车了
We shan't have need of the carriage.
很好 老爷
Very good, Your Lordship.
但夫人好像出门了 大人
I believe Her Ladyship is out, Your Lordship.
我敢说 她会及时赶回来的
I daresay she intends to return in time.
是 她之前说有事要办
Uh, yes. I believe she did mention something.
-谢谢  -老爷
·Thank you. - Your Lordship.
恐怕克拉拉前面的事
I'm afraid Clara has been detained
还没办完
at a previous appointment.
对 她的女仆刚传过话了
Yes, her maid just brought word.
我真的很抱歉 公爵夫人
I'm...really very sorry, Duchess.
别担心 你一个人来我们也开心
Please don't worry. We shall be perfectly satisfied with you.
客人来了
We have guests!
-终于来了  -奥利弗
·Finally. - Olive!
从法国乘船而的
Off the boat from France.
-你好  -奥利弗
How do you do? - Olive.
你好吗 奥利弗
How are you, Olive?
特伦查德夫人 这位是西奥
Lady Trenchard, this is Theo.
-很高兴认识你   -西奥很高兴见到你
Pleasure to meet you. - Theo, pleasure to meet you.
-阿奇博尔德  -你好吗
Archibald. - How are you?
天 我担心记不住你们所有人的名字
Oh, I'm afraid I shan't remember all these names.
别担心 夫人
Please don't worry about that, Your Ladyship.
他有时候连自己的名字都不记得
He can't remember his name half the time.
跟我们讲讲法国和巴黎的事儿吧
Tell us about France. Tell us about Paris.
说说那场革命吧
Tell us about the revolution.
哦 那是一个美丽的新世界
Oh, it's a beautiful new world.
我们拿起火枪 设立了路障
We've got muskets and barricades.
当我们唱起歌时
Quand nous chanterons
邓恩夫人 哈利路亚
Mrs. Dunn. Hallelujah!
我为您准备了君主 院长和主教的座位
I shall put you in the seat for monarchs, deans, and bishops.
首先 感谢我主
First, I thank my God
藉著耶稣基督为你们众人
through Jesus Christ for you all,
将你的信仰传遍世界
that your faith is spoken of throughout the whole world.
神是我的见证人
For God is my witness,
我为他儿子的福音 用心灵事奉他
whom I serve with my spirit in the gospel of His son...
在我祷告时
that without ceasing,
常常提及你们的名字
I make a mention of you always in my prayers.
我又求你 若照神的旨意
Making request, if by any means now at length,
如今终能得通达的路
I might have a prosperous journey
往你们那里去
by the will of God, to come unto you...